# 烹 这汁里边是没有芡的
# Pan frying. There is no starch in the sauce.
# 煎烹鸡肉串
Pan fried chicken skewers.
# 你看这有一签子
Take a look at this skewer.
# 这签子有将近五十年了
You must had those skewers for nearly 50 years.
# 这是个老物件
These are vintage skewers.
# 鸡腿肉 先搁点淀粉上浆了
Deboned leg of chicken. Mix with some starch first.
# 你怎么先搁淀粉啊
Why do you mix them with starch first?
# 都是一样的
Same thing.
# 鸡蛋
Eggs.
# 搁点酱油 冰糖老抽 盐 胡椒粉 黄酒
Some soy sauce, caramelised dark soy sauce, salt, ground pepper and rice wine.
# 这料就放完了 接着放香油
That is all the seasoning. Next, pour some sesame oil in.
# 这料都给它上齐了 已经上劲了
Mix them well.
# 香油 放香油吧 让我给说着了吧
I knew you would use sesame oil.
# 二伯说得非常准
Er Bai guessed it right.
# 你看这个鸡丁都是现成的
Already prepared chicken.
# 我们给它串好了
Put the chicken on the skewers.
# 不串直接煎也行
It is also alright to fry the chicken without skewers.
# 到时候咱们把葱姜蒜搁到小料里
Let us put chopped spring onion, ginger, and garlic with other ingredients.
# 煎呢 你要把葱姜蒜搁这里头
You need to put spring onion, ginger, and garlic in here when frying.
# 一会一煎全是黑渣子
They will be charred and turn into black bits.
# 这是真正传统菜 四五十年了
This is a real traditional dish, which has a long history of 40 or 50 years.
# 这是个老菜
Classic dish indeed.
# 煎烹牛肉串 煎烹鸡肉串 煎烹羊肉串
Pan fried beef skewers, chicken skewers, lamb skewers.
# 什么都能煎 还能煎烹虾
Everything can be pan fried, also shrimps.
# 煎烹有各种煎烹的方法
All sorts of ideas for pan-frying.
# 一种像辣酱油的 还有茄汁的
One uses Worcestershire sauce, or tomato juice, 2
# 还有一种柠檬汁的
or lemon juice,
# 还有糖醋汁的
or sweet and sour sauce.
# 各种的口味都有所不同
They all have their own unique flavour.
# 现在味道是丰富多彩
Nowadays, the taste has become richer and more flavourful.
# 煎烹就是锅里边的油要少
Pan frying requires little oil.
# 把东西煎到外焦里嫩 然后再烹
Sear and brown outside first. Then fry.
# 但是它没有完全熟 没有完全入味
But they are not cooked through yet. The flavour is not fully infused.
# 我们要靠外来的一些调味
The flavour is improved by adding additional seasonings.
# 给它做一个补充
Enhancing the flavour of the dish.
# 所以叫煎烹
So, it is called pan-frying.
# 你看过去有煎烹鱼片
In the past, there were pan fried fish slices,
# 煎烹鸡球 虾球
pan fried chicken balls, shrimp balls.
# 关键是它的调味汁和原料不同
The differences are the marinate and raw ingredients.
# 有的是酸辣的 有时候是咸鲜的
Sometimes it is hot and sour, other times savoury.
# 有的是糖醋的
Sometimes it is sweet and sour.
# 好了 真快 先烧锅
It is done. So quick. Heat up the wok first.
# 在烧锅的同时 咱把这汁调好 番茄酱
At the meantime, mix the sauce well. Tomato puree.
# 这个辣酱油是上海梅林的
This is Mei Lin spicy soy sauce (Worcestershire sauce) from Shanghai.
# 这个是最古老的一种调味汁
It is one of the most classic marinate sauces.
# 咸鲜 微辣
Savouriness, slight spicy,
# 另外它有里边有一个特殊的香味
And it has a particular aroma.
# 黄酒 冰糖老抽
Rice wine, caramelised dark soy sauce.
# 搁点糖
Add bit of sugar.
# 再来点胡椒粉
And pinch of ground pepper.
# 你看这个过程特别简单
The process looks extremely easy.
# 好了
Done.
# 煎烹啊 朝辉看啊
Chao Hui, look. Pan frying.
# 一个一个往里搁
One by one, place them in the pan.
# 别摞着 摞着煎不了了
Do not stack them up, or the meat will not be brown.
# 一煎熟了 好看吧
First round is done. Looking good?
# 煎出来的菜是干香 焦香
Seared chicken has a smoked and charred aroma.
# 这就好了 还没完全熟
Is it done? Not fully cooked yet.
# 往这一放 这菜好看吧
Plate them. Doesn’t it look delicious?
# 还没烹汁呢 一烹汁更好看
Still need to cook the sauce. It will look more delicious with sauce.
# 来点底油 小料
Drizzle of oil. Put remaining ingredients in.
# 汁儿一烹这菜就齐活
The dish will be done once we mix in the sauce.
# 烹 不勾芡
Let it fry. Do not add starch.
# 烹 这汁里边是没有芡的
Let it cook. There is no starch in the sauce.
# 辣酱油的香味出来了
The fragrance of Worcestershire sauce comes out now.
# 香气灼人 火力稍微欠点儿
Scorching aroma! Shame the stove is not powerful enough.
# 大爷翻的这两下
Da Ye, flip them over.
# 好啦 铲子
It is done.
# 这都不用搁装饰 就这样挺好看的
No need to dress up the plate. It looks delicious as it is.
# 大爷把过去的老菜
Da Ye likes to showcase those classic dishes
# 一个一个都展示出来了
one at a time.
# 让你流口水
Make a mouth-watering dish for you.
# 因为它是有油
Because it (the skewer) is greasy.
# 我们拿锡纸给它包一下把儿
Let us wrap it with some tin foil.
# 二伯 您来
After you, Er Bai.
# 这上宴会的时候一人两串
Two skewers per person was served in the banquet.
# 真嫩
So tender!
# 做工简单 但是还讲究
It is easy to make, but still requires an attention to detail.
# 味道复合味浓
Rich infused aromas.
# 辣酱油那种香气 拖着整个的菜肴
The whole dish is elevated by the aroma of Worcestershire sauce.
# 看着就想吃
Just looking at it makes you want to take a bite.
# 吃了一串还不够 又来一串
One skewer after another.
# 吃一串想两串
Eating one skewer while thinking about the other two on the plate.
# 不过这签子好啊
Well, these skewers are nice.
# 您能不能送我一套 一定
Could you give me a set? Definitely.
# --